<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing | James Lamar Foster</title>
    <link>/tag/writing/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Writing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hue1bf5cb2cb0f040263aa8336e8e6759d_14543_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>/tag/writing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Blogging Journey</title>
      <link>/post/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my first year of graduate school, a professor told me that a Ph.D. is a writing degree more than anything else. He stated I will have to learn how to write for multiple audiences and receieve feedback from multiple people.That last part - getting feedback- made me self-conscious. I&amp;rsquo;ve never had an aversion to writing but ever since grade school, I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with sharing my writing. My hesistance in sharing my writing is due to the possibility of being misunderstood and an insecurity in my ability to what I perceived to be on par with my peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my third-year of graduate school and taking classes comes to an end, I realize that I&amp;rsquo;ve shared my writing with a countless number of professors, peers, and colleagues. As a result, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen an incredible amount of growth in my writing due to how often I&amp;rsquo;ve written academic papers and the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve received. My perspective on sharing my writing has also changed. Rather than viewing it with fear and anxiety, I see it as a joy and opportunity to refine my writing. I hope to continue my writing growth by extending my writing audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to use this website as one mechanism to increase my writing audience so I can improve my writing. My desire with these posts are to share what I&amp;rsquo;m learning as a data analyst, researcher, academic, son, brother, and husband. I hope you all will join me on this journey by engaging with me via this website and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Jmar116&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Let the journey begin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
