<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Equity | James Lamar Foster</title>
    <link>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/tag/equity/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/tag/equity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Equity</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/images/icon_hue1bf5cb2cb0f040263aa8336e8e6759d_14543_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Equity</title>
      <link>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/tag/equity/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are You Reflecting?</title>
      <link>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/post/reflecting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/post/reflecting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pursuing a Ph.D. can be an isolating process, especially for minoritized students. For me, I’ve found that my family is incredibly proud of my scholastic pursuits and don’t miss an opportunity to express that to me. However, there is also the consistent and sometimes exasperating occurrence of having to explain the importance of milestones in this process, such as submitting comprehensive exams or getting a conference proposal accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursuing a Ph.D. for minoritized students can result in situations of being one of the few people who look like you in your classes. In some cases, whenever issues of inequity come up, you are tacitly looked upon for commentary about the situation and an ambassador for your race, religion, and/or ethnicity. However, this isolation can also occur in an advisory group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advisory group, in case other institutions call it something else or don&amp;rsquo;t have it, is the time when a faculty member regularly brings all of their advisees together as a group for a check-in or some structured activity. For the most part, these spaces are curated by the faculty member because they are the ones who choose who they want to advise. I see the curation of an advisory group as an opportunity for faculty members to illustrate their commitment to equity. A faculty member&amp;rsquo;s advisory group, to some extent, is a reflection of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a faculty member committed to equity, anti-racism, critical consciousness, then you have to ask yourself – what is the extent of my commitment to these ideals? Is equity something I just write about or is it something that influences my daily decisions as I interact within the different communities I am in. Is your advisory group pretty much homogenous in terms of race, language, religion, status, gender, and lived experience? If so, what does that say about your commitment to equity? Is equity something you merely write about or does it go deeper than that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way you interact with your academic community (conferences, journal reviews, scholarship, etc.), university community (faculty members, staff, grad students, etc.), and local community (neighbors, local nonprofits, community centers, etc.) should be a reflection of that commitment. What are you reflecting?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership and SEL (Under Review)</title>
      <link>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/publication/caring-journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/publication/caring-journal-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the Research Shows - Building Ranks in Action</title>
      <link>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/publication/nassp-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/publication/nassp-book/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth Film Collaborative</title>
      <link>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/project/youth-films-collaborative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jameslamarfoster.netlify.app/project/youth-films-collaborative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Youth Participatory Action Research (YPAR) engages young people in the act of conducting original research and creating multimodal texts so that they develop cultural and academic capital to operate in multiple discourse communities. Simultaneously YPAR works to create more socially just schools where youth are encouraged to take a lead in questioning policies and educational practices, including unequal power relations in our schools and society (Cammarota &amp;amp; Fine, 2008; Duncan Andrade &amp;amp; Morrell, 2008; Ginwright, Noguera, &amp;amp; Cammarota, 2006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Youth Films Collaborative (YFC) is a digital media initiative between Obama Academy (Pittsburgh Public Schools) and the Canevin Center for Educational Transformation and Social Justice at Duquesne University, in consultation with a faculty member from Nazareth College in Rochester, NY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By providing a collaborative, experimental, mentored space in schools for 11th grade students, this project aims to sharpen participants’ digital video production skills and give them new ways of engaging with a range of important critical multimodal literacy practices. More specifically, the YFC engages youth in the development of mini-documentary films on equity and social justice issues that are timely and relevant for youth-schools-communities using their “voice”. The concept of voice is used to show how people resist oppression, as seen in many feminist and post-feminist theories (Belenky, Clinchy, Goldberger, &amp;amp; Tarule, 1986; hooks, 2000). Voice also refers to instances where youth attempt to overcome and resist the ways in which schools and communities work to silence (Fine, 2003) and marginalize students by reproducing inequalities on account of race, class, gender, disability, and sexuality (Bowles &amp;amp; Gintis, 1976; Oakes, 1985). Voice is used in this presentation to question who gets to speak and who gets to make decisions with regard to school and community issues that directly impact youth. As such, the YFC seeks to cultivate reflective and change-centered processes (including the development of youth’s critical thinking and research skills), as well as practices which promote relationship building and inter-cultural dialogue with peers and adults in and outside of school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the 2104-2015, we are in the process of:
•	Identifying community issues that are important to youth
•	Asking essential research questions about the community issues
•	Collecting data and reading literature on the issue
•	Creating a mini-documentary on a social issue
•	Distributing the video online, through social media, and film festivals and in public screenings
•	Organizing “action events” around their video with the following questions - What is the change that you would like to see with regard to the community issue? How do we create action around the message in the mini-documentary film?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
