<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Race | James Lamar Foster</title>
    <link>/tag/race/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/race/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Race</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hue1bf5cb2cb0f040263aa8336e8e6759d_14543_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Race</title>
      <link>/tag/race/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cops and Robbers</title>
      <link>/post/cops-and-robbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/cops-and-robbers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I grew up in a military household. My father served in the United States Army for 20 years, 11 months, and 4 days (he would mention this often when he first retired). In typical military household fashion, my family and I moved just about every two years. Moving and visiting my Aunt Vilma in Atlanta, GA each summer were the two constants of my upbringing. Many of the places we moved to were either in Europe or in the southern region of the US. My mother is an immigrant from Panama and my father is a Florida native. My dad enlisted in the military at 17 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad is what you would call “a soldier’s soldier.” He was an Airborne Ranger who was also a marksman with air assault qualification. He was a drill sergeant and trained many other soldiers in combat warfare tactics. You would think with all these military accolades my dad was an avid gun user and had guns at home. On the contrary, my father never owned a gun outside of military use. In fact, I don’t ever remember a gun being brought in our house. Furthermore, my dad wouldn’t even allow me to have toy guns. Many of the kids I grew up around were also military brats (that’s what military kids referred to themselves as). Some of the kids I grew up around owned toy guns and would act like they were soldiers on the battlefield, shooting each other with dart guns. No matter how much I begged my dad to get me a toy gun, he would refuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One summer, when I was visiting my Aunt Vilma in Atlanta, she took me with her to run a few errands. I loved visiting Atlanta in the summer, but my aunt would always put me to work. My Aunt Vilma dedicated her life to be an elementary school teacher; she never had a significant other or kids. As a result, my sisters and I were the closest to being her children. Some of the summer tasks included helping her move items from one room to another, cleaning the garage, shining brass plant pots, or accompanying her while she ran errands. While she and I were out, we stopped by the Dollar Store. As we perused the aisles to pick up a few essentials, I saw a green and yellow dart gun on the shelf. My eight-year-old self thought this was a perfect moment to finally get my own toy gun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my Aunt Vilma added things to the basket, I stealthily slipped in the dart gun. As the cashier started ringing up everything, my aunt looked at me and said, “did you put this in my basket?” I gave a big smile and pleaded, “can I please have it, Aunt Vilma?” She gave me a stoic look and allowed the cashier to ring it up. I was so elated. As soon as I got back to my aunt’s house, I loaded up the darts and started shooting at every glass surface in the house. I shot the tv, I shot the mirrors, I shot the windows, I even shot at my sisters! My dad became aware of what I was doing and calmly asked to see the dart gun. I hesitantly gave it to him, knowing that he would not be happy. Once I handed it to him, he quickly broke it and threw it in the trash. I was furious… I ran to my mom and cried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom and dad both told me that I couldn’t have a toy gun because of how people may perceive that I have a real gun and get me in trouble. I was so confused, my other friends were allowed to have guns, why can’t I? They said plainly, it’s because people perceive Black people differently than white people. I exclaimed, that not fair. They agreed and explained that’s the world we live in. As I got older, conversations like this became more quotidian. Particularly when I was in middle school and high school and started dating and driving. Conversations of race and racism were a common occurrence growing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I reflect on it now, I realize how much racism controls/polices the way Black people interact in the world. I no longer resent my parents for not allowing me to own a toy gun. I realize they were merely trying to protect me. However, I can’t help but think about how racism has affected the way I move throughout the world, whether it’s something as simple as the toys I could play with as a child or the neighborhoods I can jog in. However, despite the limitations racism has created for me and Black people, we continue to beat the odds given to us. We continue to press forward and flourish through creativity. Despite the hardships, I wouldn’t want to be anything other than Black.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
