<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Criticality | James Lamar Foster</title>
    <link>/tag/criticality/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/criticality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Criticality</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hue1bf5cb2cb0f040263aa8336e8e6759d_14543_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Criticality</title>
      <link>/tag/criticality/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Talk to Teachers</title>
      <link>/post/a_talk_to_teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/a_talk_to_teachers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These tumultuous times have renewed my interest in reading and listening to more Black scholars who have experienced and written about hardships in the United States. I find myself going back to the writings of James Baldwin for clarity and understanding. Baldwin quenches my thirst for needing to make sense of today&amp;rsquo;s political and racial climate and my role as an educator. I turn to Baldwin because I know he will tell it to me straight, he won’t bite his tongue nor soften his tone in his writing. I know that each time I read Baldwin; he will give me the unfiltered truth without any equivocation. To help me make sense of my role in education in today&amp;rsquo;s climate, I turned to Baldwin’s &amp;ldquo;A Talk to Teachers.&amp;rdquo; Despite this talk being over 50 years old, first given in 1963, educators have plenty to glean from this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year 1963 had much uncertainty and unrest for many Americans, particularly African Americans. It started with George Wallace being elected governor of Alabama and giving an infamous speech in which he proclaimed, &amp;ldquo;segregation now, segregation tomorrow, and segregation forever!&amp;rdquo; Shortly thereafter in April, Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King Jr., Rev. Ralph Abernathy, Rev. Fred Shuttlesworth, and others were arrested in a Birmingham protest for &amp;ldquo;parading without a permit.&amp;rdquo; This is also the same time MLK penned his now famously called &amp;ldquo;Letter from Birmingham Jail.&amp;rdquo; In May, thousands of African Americans, many of them students, protested segregation in Birmingham. Public Safety Commissioner Eugene &amp;ldquo;Bull&amp;rdquo; Connor unleashed fire hoses and police dogs on protestors before arresting them. In June, Medgar Evers is assassinated in Jackson, Mississippi (his killer wasn&amp;rsquo;t convicted until 1994). In September, The 16th Street Baptist Church bombing in Birmingham, Alabama killed four children and injures 22 others. The following month in October, is when Baldwin gave his talk to teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As all this turmoil was occurring, students across the nation were getting up each day and going to school knowing what was happening in Alabama and across the country. How should a teacher address their students given the political and racial climate? Can a teacher dismiss the politics for fear of being political and continue class as planned? Should teachers seek to be neutral? I imagine Baldwin would emphatically tell teachers not to give in to the lie. In such a time like this, there is no neutral space, neutrality is a myth hoped for by the faint-hearted. As I read Baldwin&amp;rsquo;s talk, I noticed three simple lessons he gave teachers: 1) speak the truth, 2) develop young people&amp;rsquo;s critical consciousness, and 3) believe in the power within young people to change society. Baldwin gives these lessons with the understanding that in order for educators to enact these lessons, they must engage in their own critical self-reflection and questioning of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United States residents are standing on stolen Indigenous land that was built by forcibly enslaved Africans for the benefit of White people. Any deviation from this harsh reality is simply untrue. However, similar to 1963, there is a fierce campaign for schools not to teach anything that may paint the United States in a negative light, as evidenced by the federal government&amp;rsquo;s 1776 commission and attacks against critical race theory. Educators must speak the truth about what this country has stood for and who it is designed to benefit. As Baldwin states, this country is not tormented externally, but internally. In his own words, he says &amp;ldquo;it is not really a “Negro revolution” that is upsetting the country. What is upsetting the country is a sense of its own identity.&amp;rdquo; America is in a pivotal moment in that it has a decision to make on whether or not it wants to face its true identity and progress or continue promoting falsehoods and stall any potential growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Baldwin, the purpose of education is to develop independent critical thinkers. Education is needed to help students look at the world and make their own decision by questioning society and the world so they can develop their identity. Baldwin warns teachers that this kind of person is not auspicious within US society. He says the US simply wants a &amp;ldquo;citizenry which will obey the rules of society.&amp;rdquo; Compliance has been a hallmark in many classrooms, even virtual ones. Such compliance can rob students of expressing how they feel and who they are. Choosing to develop a person&amp;rsquo;s critical consciousness rather than steering them to be more compliant can lead to young people to access the agency they have to create the change this society desperately needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baldwin says society&amp;rsquo;s hope lies in the convictions of young people, convictions that will lead to self-determination and collective action. Societies change when people critically examine them and take action to change them. Baldwin once said, he criticizes America because he loves America. If it was not for a person&amp;rsquo;s commitment and love for their country, they would not develop such convictions and critique it when it does not live up to its potential. Educators have a unique role and opportunity to change the world by pouring into young people. In his talk with Nikki Giovanni, Baldwin called teaching a “revolutionary act.” The revolution begins by teachers speaking the truth, developing young people&amp;rsquo;s critical consciousness, and believing that young people can change society for the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year 2020 has been tough for everyone. I believe teachers and educators across this nation need to heed the words of James Baldwin as they did in 1963. Baldwin&amp;rsquo;s lessons are not just for the benefit of students of color, but for White students as well. As he says, &amp;ldquo;if one managed to change the curriculum in all the schools so that Negroes learned more about themselves and their real contributions to this culture, you would be liberating not only to Negroes, you’d be liberating white people who know nothing about their own history.&amp;rdquo; America can only be free when America teaches the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
