<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching | James Lamar Foster</title>
    <link>/tag/teaching/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teaching</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hue1bf5cb2cb0f040263aa8336e8e6759d_14543_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/tag/teaching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Talk to Teachers</title>
      <link>/post/a_talk_to_teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/a_talk_to_teachers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These tumultuous times have given me a renewed interest in reading and listening more to James Baldwin. My interest stems from my desperate need to make sense of today&amp;rsquo;s political climate and my role as an educator. I turn to Baldwin because he isn&amp;rsquo;t safe. Meaning, I know that each time I read Baldwin, he will give me the unfiltered truth without any equivocation. I recently decided to reread Baldwin&amp;rsquo;s October 1963 speech entitled &amp;lsquo;A Talk to Teachers.&amp;rsquo; For me, this is one of those speeches where you can&amp;rsquo;t help but nod your head in agreement after each point and ask yourself - &amp;lsquo;what year was this written?&amp;rsquo; Despite being over 50 years old, educators have plenty to glean from the lessons Baldwin outlines in this speech. My goal with this essay is to contexxtualize the year 1963 and James Baldwin&amp;rsquo;s speeach, share some of Baldwin&amp;rsquo;s lessons, and explain why they are relevant for educators in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1963 was a year of much uncertainty and unrest for many Americans, particularly African Americans. It started with George Wallace being elected govenor of Alabama and giving an infamous speech in which he proclaimed &amp;ldquo;segregation now, segregation tomorrow, and segregation forever!&amp;rdquo; Shortly thereafter in May, thousands of African Americans, many of them students, protested segrgation in Brimingham. Public Safety Commissioner Eugene &amp;ldquo;Bull&amp;rdquo; Connor unleashed fire hoses and police dogs on protestors prior to arresting them. As all this turmoil was occuring, students across the nation were getting up the following day and going to school despite listening on the radio and television what was happening in Alabama and across the country. I would imagine you coould cut the tension in each classroom with a knife. How should a teacher address her students given the political and racial climate? Can a teacher dismiss the politics for fear of being political and continue class as planned? Baldwin urges teachers not to give into the lie - speak the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baldwin implores teachers to speak the truth about the making of this country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April 12 – Martin Luther King Jr., Ralph Abernathy, Fred Shuttlesworth and others are arrested in a Birmingham protest for &amp;ldquo;parading without a permit&amp;rdquo;. April 16 – Martin Luther King Jr. issues his Letter from Birmingham Jail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 12 – Medgar Evers is assassinated in Jackson, Mississippi. His killer, Byron De La Beckwith, is convicted in 1994.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;August 28 – Martin Luther King Jr. delivers his &amp;ldquo;I Have a Dream&amp;rdquo; speech on the steps of the Lincoln Memorial to an audience of at least 250,000, during the March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October 22 – Chicago Public Schools Boycott, also known as Freedom Day. Protesting segregationist policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 15 – The 16th Street Baptist Church bombing in Birmingham, Alabama kills four children and injures 22.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
