<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graduate School | James Lamar Foster</title>
    <link>/tag/graduate-school/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/graduate-school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Graduate School</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hue1bf5cb2cb0f040263aa8336e8e6759d_14543_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Graduate School</title>
      <link>/tag/graduate-school/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are You Reflecting?</title>
      <link>/post/reflecting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/reflecting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pursuing a Ph.D. can be an isolating process, especially for minoritized students. For me, I’ve found that my family is incredibly proud of my scholastic pursuits and don’t miss an opportunity to express that to me. However, there is also the consistent and sometimes exasperating occurrence of having to explain the importance of milestones in this process, such as submitting comprehensive exams or getting a conference proposal accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursuing a Ph.D. for minoritized students can result in situations of being one of the few people who look like you in your classes. In some cases, whenever issues of inequity come up, you are tacitly looked upon for commentary about the situation and an ambassador for your race, religion, and/or ethnicity. However, this isolation can also occur in an advisory group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advisory group, in case other institutions call it something else or don&amp;rsquo;t have it, is the time when a faculty member regularly brings all of their advisees together as a group for a check-in or some structured activity. For the most part, these spaces are curated by the faculty member because they are the ones who choose who they want to advise. I see the curation of an advisory group as an opportunity for faculty members to illustrate their commitment to equity. A faculty member&amp;rsquo;s advisory group, to some extent, is a reflection of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a faculty member committed to equity, anti-racism, critical consciousness, then you have to ask yourself – what is the extent of my commitment to these ideals? Is equity something I just write about or is it something that influences my daily decisions as I interact within the different communities I am in. Is your advisory group pretty much homogenous in terms of race, language, religion, status, gender, and lived experience? If so, what does that say about your commitment to equity? Is equity something you merely write about or does it go deeper than that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way you interact with your academic community (conferences, journal reviews, scholarship, etc.), university community (faculty members, staff, grad students, etc.), and local community (neighbors, local nonprofits, community centers, etc.) should be a reflection of that commitment. What are you reflecting?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Blogging Journey</title>
      <link>/post/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my first year of graduate school, a professor told me that a Ph.D. is a writing degree more than anything else. He stated I will have to learn how to write for multiple audiences and receieve feedback from multiple people.That last part - getting feedback- made me self-conscious. I&amp;rsquo;ve never had an aversion to writing but ever since grade school, I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with sharing my writing. My hesistance in sharing my writing is due to the possibility of being misunderstood and an insecurity in my ability to what I perceived to be on par with my peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my third-year of graduate school and taking classes comes to an end, I realize that I&amp;rsquo;ve shared my writing with a countless number of professors, peers, and colleagues. As a result, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen an incredible amount of growth in my writing due to how often I&amp;rsquo;ve written academic papers and the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve received. My perspective on sharing my writing has also changed. Rather than viewing it with fear and anxiety, I see it as a joy and opportunity to refin my writing. I hope to continue my writing growth by extending my writing audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to use this website as one mechanism to increase my writing audience so I can improve my writing. My desire with these posts are to share what I&amp;rsquo;m learning as a data analyst, researcher, academic, son, brother, and husband. I hope you all will join me on this journey by engaging with me via this website and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Jmar116&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Let the journey begin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
